The reason Bitcoin to me is the ultimate
choice, it is the S&P 500 of 10 years
from now, is not because of anything
special about it from an innovation
perspective. It's because it doesn't
suffer from time because it's not based
on time. Everything else is based on
time and people are going to have to
start to process that cuz the world is
spinning much faster than it ever has.
What's going on guys? Today we got a
great conversation with Jordy Visser. In
this, we talk about AI stocks, why it's
bounced so hard off the bottom, how
Jord's thinking about interest rates,
inflation in the recent report, and then
we get into what's going on in the
crypto world, blockchain companies, and
figure technologies is absolutely
exploding. He explains how he thinks
about that. And then we have a very
philosophical conversation about time
and why AI agents may be changing the
way you should think about earnings and
different economic interest that's going
on in the market. Here's my latest
conversation with Jordy Visser. All
right, Jordy, the bears are in
disbelief. The S&P's at a new all-time
high. The bull market continues. Woo!
What's going on? Why are stocks still
going higher?
>> Everyone hates AI, so that's why it's
going higher. Um,
what do you want to say? Earnings are
growing. Uh, and the S&P is not growing
at the same pace as earnings right now.
So, right now, we're headed for
year-over-year at above 30%. The S&P
when you annualize the performance,
we're going to come in, assuming that we
continue at this pace, somewhere in
around 20%. So, we've seen multiple
compression. Everyone uh started to
build in rate hikes. We've got inflation
that just keeps surprising on the lower
end, but people keep worrying that it's
going to go higher. Um I think it's
actually kind of amazing that we have
rate hikes built in at all. Two-year
rates are still well above the Fed funds
rate right now. Um so, I I think in
general when you go through everything
and you realize we just had a negative
payroll job number, we had inflation on
the lower end. We had PPI surprise
there. We had the retail sales number
which came out soft. The economy is
good, but most of the good is happening
with inside AI. And I think we're just
at a point where people are having a a
hard time embracing this. And I just
will say for for valid reasons,
particularly when you look at some of
the AI charts, if you go to the Cosby
and you visually look at the chart, I
mean, it broke down hard. It kind of
looks a lot like Bitcoin. It just
happened in a month as opposed to nine
months. But here's the reality. It's
still up 70% year to date or yeah, the
Cosby 200 is. And that just makes it a
scenario that I think people are going
to remain bearish the entire time and
it's a reflection of them not
understanding AI and I think this is
going to be a problem that continues. So
we'll be climbing a wall of AI worry for
a long time.
>> You basically called the bottom of the
AI uh kind of draw down here. You said
situational awareness was the kind of
capitulation event. You thought that we
had bottomed. It does look like we've
done that. Um you have a AI thematic
portfolio that you've put together. Um
people can go find this at 22V research.
I think the URL is ai.22vresearch.com
and that portfolio has if I remember
correctly like a 100 names or so. And it
has bounced super hard off of the
bottom. talk a little bit as to like the
themes that you've put in there and then
why do you look at this as uh somewhat
of like an index of the AI trade.
>> Right. First of all, because it's a a
pet peeve of mine, there's no such thing
as calling bottoms or calling tops. Now,
um I think for a lot of people who
trade, they're trying to do that. That
is not possible. What I do believe is
possible is that um you
change your views in this kind of eb and
flow to where the riskreward increases.
So when situational awareness happened
and we talked about it what I said at
that time both here and on the video
that I do every week was that the
probabilities and the riskreward from
this point are fantastic because we had
a obvious market clearing event. what I
said in that weekend video, we we
absolutely probably have a hundred other
situational awareness situations,
not to the same degree and not big
enough to matter. We've seen some hedge
funds be down 25 30% for the month. So,
there were a lot of losses, but when you
disclose and something that big gets
happened, a lot of people were hedging
in front of it and so you're get an
increased probability. I just want to
bring that up because I think the
mistake people are going to make with AI
is trying to pick tops and bottoms. When
I got out of Micron, the price of Micron
is still above where it was when I sold
out. What I said on the show was at
below 900. I started buying some. Well,
I didn't pick the bottom. It's above
there now. It went above it once. It
went below it. I got to buy some stuff
with a seven handle at 700 and change,
which was still above where I was. I'm
not trying to pick tops and bottoms. If
you use Micron as an example, why would
you ever buy something at a higher
price? Well, because I got new
information, first of all, the new
information was that the earnings came
in better than expected and they signed
long-term agree agreements, meaning
they're not going to have cyclical
earnings the way they did in the past.
Number two, the compute situation.
Everyone started to worry because of the
open source where to me the compute
demand is actually accelerated and DRAM
prices have gone higher. So when you add
in the new information, I just reset my
brain and I go, you know what? I'm not
going to be as big as I was when it was
600 or 700, but that was after an eight
bagger. I'm going to start building a
position because I believe between now
and the end of the year, the probability
of it being higher than it is today
based on the new information has
increased. That is the way you think
about things. And that way, just like
I've said before, my father trained me
how to handicap horse races. All of the
odds in the market are based on new
information and have people cleanse
their system. We've seen massive
deleveraging. So for the AI trade as as
a just a general thing, we've seen it go
up and the volume has been very very
low. The volume getting out was much
higher which I highlighted on the
videos. Those are capitulation type
events. People have to remember that a
lot of demand soak things up at lower
prices. And then when you start rallying
on lower volume, that's different than
the way people are trained. But I think
what it says to me is people are now
caught missing out. The earnings have
been fantastic almost across the board.
And it's not just my 100 name index, the
10 name index, which are the test the 10
names I selected that were the most
correlated. They're in each of the
different components, meaning like
optical, semiconductors. Um, you've got
Nvidia in there. You've got Intel
because CPUs as opposed to GPUs. You've
got Marll in there for the optical side
on the semiconductors, but then you also
have Caterpillar and you have Corning
and things like that. that one has
bounced back more than 50% of the fall.
And part of the strength that has been
there is it's not allowing anyone to get
back in because there's really not been
any corrections. So, that's the way I'd
view it. I try to help people with this,
but the reality is you don't pick tops
and bottoms. You want to ride this thing
for the next five years because demand
is still greater than it was at the
beginning of the year.
>> All right. So, you're calling the top
and calling tops and bottoms. I got you.
Um,
>> yes. Never, never, never tell me I've
picked a bottom or a top. It's bad ju
guuju, but it's also not true.
>> All right. Um, inflation came in and it
was much weaker than people, I think,
were predicting. And I had a guy say,
"Oh, Jordy Visser was wrong." And I
actually defended you. I said, "I don't
think that's true." I think that you
were very clear that there was kind of
this probabilistic outcome of higher
inflation, but different variations of
that. But I think that what we saw and
what appears to have been the peak of
inflation was well within that
probabilistic, you know, kind of
spectrum that you had outlined. How are
you thinking about this specific
inflation report? And then how are you
thinking about it going forward and
whether that's going to continue to be
kind of a buoy to the stock market?
>> So I I'm going to use a word here that I
used in a sub a post that I did for the
subscribers, but I also posted in
Substack because I think it was that
important. And we briefly talked about
this last week um about the dollar yen
intervention and how important it is
from a contextual basis. And you're
going to start hearing me say this all
the time because
the part of inflation is in the context
of tariffs, in the context of oil prices
soaring higher, in the context of
fertilizer, all of the things that
happen in the context of nominal GDP
accelerating
inflation. Theoretically, if you put all
those together, you'd think they would
be much higher. core CPI at the
beginning of at the end of last year was
2.6% year-over-year. Here we are, it's
now 2.5%, which is basically at the
lowest level. When you go through
trueflation, when you go through trim
mean, when you go through I could name
and I do this each week. I actually
created a composite.
Inflation to me
is something that should be higher than
it is today based on everything we're
seeing. And contextually, I will argue
again and again that we're starting to
see the deflationary pressures of AI. As
AI agents have come this year, we focus
on the demand side that is going. But
one of the things that's happening is
car insurance. You're getting more
startup car insurance places that are
willing to sell car insurance at lower
prices, places like Lemonade. And if
every company was using AI in their
business, then their margins were
improving, then they'd be able to lower
prices. So theoretically, if profit
margins are going higher and the
competition using AI is finally starting
to see some of the benefits and
productivity is coming, you will start
to see the deflationary pressure start
showing up sooner rather than later. Um,
I appreciate you defending me. Um,
anyone who watches this, if you're going
to judge people on things they say, then
you're basically saying I don't want you
to make any predictions. If you're going
to critique them for being wrong, I
don't critique people for making
predictions. I critique them for being
stubborn and for not adjusting to new
information and changing as the data
changes. That is a basian mindset that
every investor has to have. So, if
you're a trader sitting at home and
you're looking for calls and going,
"Well, I I followed what they said and
and and they were wrong." Well, you're
not making your own decisions.
Everything that I say should not be used
as investment advice. You guys read this
in disclaimers. What is supposed to
happen to go back to the inflation side
is in a contextual side, inflation is
far weaker than I would have expected.
And that says to me that going forward
from here, if oil prices end up the year
at 65, I'm actually shocked oil prices,
given the fact the war is still going on
and there's no agreement, are not
higher. And you know, one of the reasons
that's starting to show up that they're
not higher, you're starting to read more
that the pipelines are being built, the
getting rid of Hormuz as an important
thing, that's new information. Is it
here today? No. But if the oil market
thinks it's going to be here in 3 years,
which they do, well then all of a sudden
this Hormuse thing doesn't matter for
threeyear prices, it just matters for
one year price. And clearly at this
point, something else is going on. So
this is kind of an answer to your
question, but it's also a learning
lesson for people that when you hear
basian philosophy, when you hear basian
mindset, you have to be willing to
change your view based on the data
that's provided. That is the reason why
we do these data driven things. I will
never sit there and show people my
guesses on things without providing some
sort of documentation, proof or data to
support the reasoning behind it. And if
it changes, I'll turn AISL slowdown
turns into situational panic. That's two
different things. So
>> now when we go and we look at um the
intersection of crypto, AI, finance,
investing, etc. I think you and I spend
all of our time at that intersection.
And some weeks we talk more about AI
stuff. Some weeks we talk more about
Bitcoin and crypto stuff. Some weeks,
frankly, we just talk about macro
environment and what's going on in
geopolitics or interest rates, etc. Um,
there's a story that frankly I've been
involved with for a long time, but even
I don't think I quite appreciated how
good of a company Figure Technologies
has become now. Um, they did earnings
this past week and they reported revenue
growing at over 100% year-over-year and
EBA growing at more than 50%
year-over-year. That gives them kind of
this rule of 150 which puts them in a
very very rare um, you know, group of
companies. like two other companies in
the world uh in the public markets that
are large that uh that that fit that.
When you look at that business to me,
what's fascinating given kind of the
backdrop of what we talk about, they've
got some AI and automation. They've got
obviously a blockchain. They are
involved in traditional finance in terms
of lending which is very susceptible and
sensitive to interest rates. like they
may be one of the companies out of a
handful that are living at the
intersection of this and they're both
benefiting from it but also they're
having to deal with all the challenges
whether it's regulatory or technological
change etc. And so maybe let's just
spend a couple minutes talking about,
you know, we've said Eli Liy was growing
revenue, I think at like 50%
year-over-year, and they're a trillion
dollar business. Well, here's another
example of a company that is
accelerating. They're growing revenue at
more than 100% year-over-year. EBA at 50
plus% a year, doing hundreds of millions
of dollars of revenue. And it feels
like, hey, this may start to become many
more stories of this rather than just
one, you know, one company or two
companies for us to point at. Right.
You and I have have spoken um I don't
know how far we're we're a year and
almost a half into us doing this show.
>> Best year and a half of my life.
>> Yeah, it's been good for me, too. Yeah,
you've you've you've had a lot of
children. There's been a lot of things
going on.
>> No, no, just just cuz I talk to you
every Friday.
>> Oh, okay. All right. Uh, I'm going to
explain a couple things here as to um
why people are making a big mistake on
crypto in terms of not doing all of
their homework on it because I think
you've hit on a very important point.
The next phase of what I'm going to do
with my weekly YouTubes and what I'm
doing with my subscriber paywall is
basically to prepare people to
understand how figure can actually be
growing at the pace that they are
despite the regulatory side. So, let's
go through how business gets done. If
you buy a house, when's the last time
you bought a house or apartment or
anything?
>> I uh prefer to be asset light there,
Jordy.
>> Okay. So, let's assume for example,
>> like a couple years ago.
>> Okay. And how long of a process and how
arduous is it to go from you find a
house, you make a decision, you agree on
a buyer and a seller. From that point,
think about how long it takes even if
you're going to pay them in all cash.
Fastest I've seen it happen is uh
closing in two weeks and everyone gets
really uncomfortable because they think
that's too fast and everyone freaks out
and they're like well let's just do 30
days but usually I don't know 60-day
close something like that. So imagine if
the house closed and then immediately
that day like you bought it and it was
that day then everyone gets to go sell
another home and you get to have more
transactions. And so the companies that
are benefiting and let's just use figure
as an example. If they're able to
eliminate all the middlemen and they're
able to eliminate the friction of all of
the money thing, the credit checks, all
of the things that go on all of those
hands that equal the 30 days in an
allcash transaction. Once you start
getting into I need to borrow the money
for a mortgage, which most people do,
the whole process takes forever. Well,
guess what? GDP suffers from that.
Earnings for a company suffer from that.
If they could do these transactions much
faster at a slightly lower price than
where the fiat system is trading, then
gradually over time you're going to
start seeing deflation. You're going to
see more transactions. And what you
start getting into is what Caitlyn Long
talked about. The velocity of money, the
velocity of transactions is going to
increase significantly
because we measure things in human time
year-over-year. Why do we care about a
year? What what does year-over-year
mean? If you can do the same amount of
transactions in a quarter as you used to
do in a year. Well, when figure has
similar growth numbers to what an AI
company does, meaning their transactions
are growing at 50, 60, 70%.
I think people need to start investing
and looking into this because every day
that AI agents become a reality right
now most of this stuff is happening
without true agentic world meaning hey
go out and find me a house that I want
to buy or rent or do whatever and just
get it done for me and it's done within
minutes or you buy a house and
immediately the next day you're like you
know what I put all this money into the
house what I want to do right now is go
borrow on it because something else came
up you have to go through if you just
bought a house and now you want to go
borrow on it. Well, that's a that's a
process that's not going to work. Why
are you borrowing? What's going on? If
everything is tokenized, you can start
to see how the economy starts to move at
a faster pace. So, when people look at
S&P earnings growth of year-over-year of
30 plus%. And I sit there and go, "Guys,
you're not realizing that the beauty of
the math in this is as Agentic and
crypto starts to impact and intersect
together, the ability for the agents to
transact faster needs the wallets and
the money and all of the guardrails that
go on. It might take another two years,
three years. And this is why the
regulatory side clarity act has an
impact on hedge funds looking at this.
But at some point the disruptive nature
of AI allowing the crypto companies to
grow fast the companies with the
financial guardrails that are starting
with DeFi and all these things. This is
why I'm creating an index which
converges on the crypto tokens on
different verticals or sectors of the
future combined with the public
companies like Figure, like Hood, like
PayPal, like Coinbase, the ones that are
already public. This intersection is
going to be one of the most explosive
growth points we've seen because these
companies are going to be disrupting
from the middlemen that cost you time
and money every single day. Those
dollars are going to flow into the
landscape of the most efficient places.
Mark my words, you will all be paying
attention to crypto a year from now. So
when you're looking at the prices and
you're looking at Bitcoin, I know it's
anxietyfilled. It's not going up. Oh,
the Clarity Act is there. Oh, the Fed's
going to raise three times. Just
remember this is all noise with inside a
secular trend. So what's interesting is
um when I first uh invested in um Figure
I was uh through Morgan Creek and at the
time they basically were saying hey we
are going to create a decentralized DTCC
kind of a settlement you know type
organization and what they very quickly
realized is you could build the
technology but no one wanted to use it.
No one believed that it had any value
and so Mike Kagny is a a fantastic
entrepreneur. He said, "Well, I'll prove
to you that this is valuable." And so,
he started actually originating loans
himself, and then he was basically
selling them on the back end to uh to
these providers. So, he said, "If I need
one side of the marketplace to show up
and I can't convince anyone, I'll just
go do it myself." And what I found so
interesting about it was their pitch
early on, definitely to the consumer,
but even to investors, was we can issue
a heliloc in tell somebody in 5 minutes
whether they're going to get it or not,
and they can have the money in their
account within like 5 days, I think, was
like the promise. And the way that they
did this was you basically went in and
you connected your bank account and then
they could read through your bank
account and find all kinds of
interesting data points. They could see,
you know, how much money do you make and
verify that or where do you work as the
employer because you get a direct
deposit. All of this like quoteunquote
automation had nothing to do with the
blockchain. It was all about using
modern technologies, not even AI
necessarily, just using plaid
connections and being smart and all that
kind of stuff, but it was a better user
experience. And so they went from
nothing to the third largest HELOC
originator in the country. very quickly.
And the reason why I bring that up is
because I think that we're seeing this.
Robin Hood is doing it. I think Robin
Hood now has seven or eight different
lines of business that do at least $100
million of revenue. They have a
brokerage business, but they got a lot
of businesses, right? And so if you
start to just go through Stripe, Robin
Hood, you know, Figure, etc., It almost
feels like the technologists have
realized that they are going to be able
to automate and rip out these
inefficiencies in a way that is going to
accelerate growth and also drop the
expenses that are associated with
delivering these services. And so then
the question shifts to okay well if
you're JP Morgan, Goldman Sachs, if
you're Mastercard and Visa and some of
these guys are those just shorts like
are they screwed or do you see them
starting to say wait a second we got to
get in this game as well? like how as an
investor do you think through we know
the the the new tech kind of finance
type companies they're all doing very
well how do you then go and evaluate the
kind of banks or legacy finance firms um
you know in a portfolio
>> okay so this is this is a complex
question which has a complex answer
>> okay
>> um I spent a lot of time by the way
looking at figures business I probably
would be would speak of them more both
here and on my if they had taken the
time for management to actually speak
with me, which I requested um to learn
more because a lot of the things that
you mentioned on the HELOC side, I
wanted to connect them to tokenization.
I wanted to connect them to the thought
process and that's what I asked when
they when they approached me and I said,
"Hey, I'd be very interested in learning
more about the business, but I got to
talk to management. I've I've been a
partner at a Fortune 500 company. I've
run a bunch of businesses. I have my own
business. I'm just interested in
knowing." But they were so busy that
that's a reflection of how fast they're
growing. Also,
>> we'll fix that, Jordy. Don't worry.
>> No, no, no. Don't fix anything,
>> Mike. Come on, man.
>> No. And and what I did is I watched a
lot of YouTubes with Mike. I went
through a lot of the business. I was
very interested from my macro mosaic
perspective to the question you're
answering you're asking. And the reason
is for me, I'm a dot connector. If they
grow super fast and they apply pressure
to JP Morgan, what how is JP Morgan
going to compete? Well, number one, JP
Morgan has all the eyeballs. They have
all the money. They have the deposits.
They have all this stuff there. So,
theoretically, if they can do this
business, they'll be able to compete and
knock them out. That's what happened in
the past. The problem is in today's
world, people, the reason JP Morgan is a
short, not in an absolute basis, but
relative to companies like Figure and
the other tokenbased companies that are
going to grow faster, is because they
don't have the legacy employees. And I
want to make sure everyone understands
this. JP Morgan is a bureaucracy.
They've accumulated so many companies.
Chemical like I you can go through the
list of banks that they've accumulated.
Jaime Diamond came from a bank. Um
it's not that their business isn't good,
it's that they can only grow at human
speed. For them to actually convert into
a cryptoast
business, it's very hard to do that.
You're seeing what's happened to
Salesforce.com. That's an AI company
who's out there selling a Gentic site.
It's very hard to do that. Google,
Demisabus, and Jeff Dean just left. This
is a major story. Why? And no, I know
Demisabas didn't leave yet, but the
story is that he was going to leave.
>> Why did those guys leave? Because Google
is a bureaucracy. Think about that,
guys. A company that is growing their
revenues at 30 plus% is a bureaucracy.
This is a problem for the future. So
eventually, will these companies go
down? I don't know. I just know right
now they're not growing as fast. That's
why the portfolio that I put together is
the receivers of the infrastructure
right now. And their earnings are
growing far faster. Micron's earnings
are growing far faster than anything
that Ford, to use an example, can do.
Ford can't grow their revenues any
better. How are they going to do that?
They're an old company with a lot of
debt and a lot of pensions. the world is
evolving into what you're describing and
companies like Figure and companies that
are inside the crypto and the AI world
are just going to grow faster and that's
why the AI native companies will
eventually disrupt the public companies
and this is why I spend my time on the
merging of the old world that is full of
middlemen that the middlemen are the S&P
500 the companies like figure are not
middlemen they are actually trying to
disrupt that business and the heliloc
side gets into how Can I borrow money on
my house? It gets back to the
tokenization side. So eventually over
time when you get everything on the
blockchain and you can do everything
real time.
Speed of AI is what's changing. And I'll
leave you with this. I'm spending more
time on this concept of time.
AI moves at a speed that our brains
cannot handle, that businesses cannot
handle. Crypto will be connected to AI
agents very soon. the stable coin
volumes and the transactions are going
already at paces that we've never seen
before. Every day it's only going to
more intensify. The reason Bitcoin to me
is the ultimate choice. It is the S&P
500 of 10 years from now is not because
of anything special about it from an
innovation perspective. It's because it
doesn't suffer from time because it's
not based on time. Everything else is
based on time. And people are going to
have to start to process that because
the world is spinning much faster than
it ever has. Today's episode is brought
to you by Arch Public. Arch Public has
just expanded its agentic trading
platform beyond crypto. So pay
attention. This is a big one. Now they
are automating strategies across stocks,
commodities, and ETFs. And I think that
this is going to be huge. You can now
automatically take profits when one
market hits new all-time highs and
rotate that capital into other markets
showing more opportunity. Whether you're
rotating capital into AI stocks, gold,
if you're investing in the S&P 500, or
you're accumulating Bitcoin, Arch Public
brings real discipline and automation to
your investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Arch Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to
archpubic.com
right now. Connect with their team, set
up a time, bring your accountant if
you'd like. Then you can learn what
automated trading can do for you.
archpub.com.
Now, when we start thinking about these
uh these different businesses, one of
the rumors is that Anthropic is going to
go public uh here in the next couple of
months. And what I'm starting to see is
obviously these companies have been
growing incredibly quickly. They started
to plateau a little bit, but it does
feel like there's preparation for public
markets. And I think that all of these
companies go through this to some
degree, but there's a number of OpenAI
executives who have stepped down.
There's now a rumor that maybe actually
it's OpenAI who's kind of forcing their
hand and saying, "Hey, let let's change
out some people." Anthropic is
supposedly kind of tightening their
belt, getting ready to go public.
When you look at something like a
figure, when you look at something like
a Robin Hood, these kind of like digital
native or AI friendly type companies
that are not necessarily large language
models, but they are definitely more AI
friendly than the big banks or you know
all these other kind of incumbent
businesses. Does that get you excited to
see the large language models come into
the market or do you still think that
those companies may um have some work to
do before they become public? And the
reason I asked that is I have talked to
I don't know four or five investors over
the last month or so that have literally
told me they have money sitting aside in
cash because they are waiting to deploy
it into the large language model labs
when they go public. And so it feels
like they're like, "Oh, if that happens
in the next month or so, I don't want to
be invested somewhere else and then have
to go sell and incur taxes, etc." And I
took that as a little surprising because
that's not really the way I invest. And
you know, it it it was something I
hadn't heard before.
Um, so there's a lot in that question.
I'm going to gear it towards um, the
first thing you said, let's use
anthropic because everyone has now heard
that they're on by the end of this year,
people expect them to be, let's say, at
a 120 billion ARR.
The reason I emphasize the ARR,
you know what that is? That's human
time. So how many people actually know
at the end of this year if I say well
the ARR now for this month is 120
billion that makes it real easy. So that
means that that would make that final
month at 10 billion.
At some point you're still annualizing
things on human time. Meaning we know
that on something you brought up and I
think this is the important point. Open
source is happening and AI native
businesses are not using anthropic the
way that big companies are using them.
Anthropic's revenues are being dominated
by the big companies. the big Fortune
500 companies, the middlemen trying to
figure a way to replace their employees
with the LLMs. The other thing you and I
have talked about is specialized models
are probably going to win. Meaning an
open source model that's trained on your
data is probably better. I've said that
the frontier models are really critical
because you need to have models that are
trying to be 2,000 IQ, not ones that are
trying to stop at 150 IQ, which is all
you need to replace human beings. So,
ANA businesses don't need 2,000 IQ.
For big companies that are very complex,
for governments, for science, for all of
these things, we need 2,000 IQs because
the systems are extremely complex. But
for running a business where you're just
trying to have revenues higher than
expense, you probably don't need to have
2,000 IQs, you just need to have this
unless you're trying to build the
biggest business on the planet. So the
reason I bring all this up is we're
getting to the point where as people use
AI more and more, they're going to start
to realize that a lot of these numbers
that are being thrown around, the
biggest risk to anthropic is not whether
their ARR gets to a trillion dollars
next year. It's probably more if they're
only at 200 billion next year,
their valuation is going to come down
sharply because once it's not a plateau,
once the growth rate actually starts to
slow in a meaningful discernable way,
the valuation is going to come down and
we've seen that already in the market.
So whenever I say multiple compression
to people, multiple compression gets
back to terminal value. terminal value
gets back into if something's not
growing close to the pace of AI. So when
Palanteer reported earnings, their
company revenue is growing at 149%.
It's less than I think a billion dollars
still, but Palanteer is growing rapidly
now. They've had a bad year relative to
Anthropic, but their revenues are
growing extremely fast. And so if you
get to the point where, okay, that's a
year-over-year basis. Santhropic right
now is clearly growing faster than
year-over-year because if they've gone
from 1 billion to 2 billion to 3 billion
to 4 billion each month and they're
going to finish the year around 10
billion, but their growth rate is
actually starting to slow down. I think
people are going to get into this
concept of time again and understanding.
So that was a long way of basically
going through. I think everything that
you brought up for people, we're now
doing what used to take 10 years in 3
months. You have to be careful that when
the growth rate starts to slow, that
means competition has come into your
world and that's going to affect every
investor over the course of the next
decade.
>> Can I um give you a uh a non-technical
indicator as to uh the proliferation of
AI and the adoption of AI that uh is
sounding the alarm in my life?
>> I love when you first of all ask me for
approval to say anything on your own
show. That that's a sign of respect.
Secondly, I like when you get serious
because there's usually a joke in there.
So, go ahead. Well, it's like uh you
ever seen the joke uh when a toddler
gives you a sticker, that's a sign of
respect in their culture, right? That
that's ask me asking you is a sign of
respect in my culture. Um all right, so
my wife, amazing woman. Um up until two
weeks ago, the use of AI was pretty much
supercharged Google. She would ask a
question. She liked that it would give
her really, you know, uh kind of
thorough answers. um it remembered
things about her and so she could you
know kind of have conversations but it
was basically she was using it as a
replacement for Google
as you can imagine some of the questions
I'm like what are you talking to you
know what are you asking the AI whatever
but like that that's what she was using
it for she just signed up for her very
first what I'll call AI agent or AI
co-pilot it is supposed to be a family
household manager
just shut the internet down like it's
is over. We we we have infiltrated the
moms with the AI. This thing texts her
every morning. Here's a bunch of things
on the to-do list. Here's things that
you have coming up. Here's things that
you told me. She's, you know, using it
as a back and forth like a almost like a
friend or an assistant, right? And she's
really kind of in this and I she doesn't
even know I'm going to bring this up. Uh
but I've been watching over the last,
you know, two weeks or so. It has
changed the way that she thinks about
technology, AI, etc. but it's changing
what she's doing on a day-to-day basis.
And I think that one, it's reducing like
mental load. And so, she's like
outsourcing the intelligence. She's
using it somewhat as like a to-do list,
but also it is connecting dots that
she's like, "Wow, this is really
helpful." The reason why I use it as
like the the nontechnical indicator when
you get to the mom's, it's over. Like
the technology is not going away. It has
finally reached the like product market
fit, you know, etc. Now, she may not be
that unique and she may even be a late
adopter. Like, there's probably other
people who have been using, you know,
all this kind of stuff, whatever. And
we've talked previously about the woman
who homeschools her kids and she's been
using it to create, you know, everything
from coloring books to lesson plans, you
know, all this stuff.
It feels like the conversation is
turning from data centers are bad, AI is
bad, it's going to take our jobs, etc.
to now you're starting to see the
positive impact on everyday Americans
lives and they're realizing there's
nuance. They're not 100% on board.
They're not going to just walk away from
the data center debate, etc. But you can
see the way that the the companies are
talking, Facebook, Anthropic, they're
talking about team human, right? They're
they've softened their language that
they're starting to say, "Hey, this is
here to help you." To me, that's
actually a massive tailwind for all of
the AI stocks because you're not going
to have people fighting it as hard. And
so, if people think it's valuable, they
start using this stuff and you don't
have people fighting it at every step. I
mean, what another 2, three years of the
AI trade probably now, you know, we've
got the foundation for and like here we
go.
you're you're bringing things that just
um as I'm listening I just keep
I keep thinking of which parts of um I
think a lot um I have a lot of
conversations with with AI and I do it
in my car I do it everywhere. So I'm
going to give you an answer for Paulina.
It's surprising to me just because I've
I've read her work. I've written things
about the work that she's gone. She's a
smart woman who has deep thoughts. Um,
>> she also thinks a lot, Jordy. Don't
worry.
>> Yeah. No, no, no. And again, I I wrote a
paper where I referenced the book. It
had an it had an impact on the way that
I think about things. And that happens a
lot with AI. So, one of the reasons that
I publicly say that I hated school is
because I think school is a complete
waste of time. I always thought that.
So, this is not something new. And to be
honest with you, whatever people think
of me, my brain is my best asset. Like,
it works really hard. But here's the
thing. Everyone who has a child that's
been annoyed at some point when the kid
is in the back seat asking a question
and then it, hey, why is the sky blue?
And then you try to give an answer and
then they follow it up with another
question and then you give it another
one and finally you're like, hey, can
you stop asking me questions? You don't
want to stop that. And with AI, it never
stops. If I have a question about
anything,
the the charts that I create, a lot of
them are created by AI doing the work
for me. I'm going to show a bunch of
things this weekend that I created.
People don't realize that when I'm on
AI, when I'm in my car and I'm talking
to Grock, this is a conversation. When
you use Google, you're getting you're
searching for answers and then you get
that answer and you think that's the
answer there that I I hate to tell
people. My father was 100% right.
Nothing you hear from me, from Anthony,
from uh any expert is truth. It is an
opinion and opinions get incorporated by
you into your own brain. And you should
never take anything. That's why again
what I say is not investment advice.
What I'm saying is I'm doing a lot of
work, probing thought to give to you for
you to make your own decision. You don't
have to believe me that I think Bitcoin
is going to go higher. If I believed it
was 100%, I'd have all my money in it.
I'd be leveraged and go through it. I
know there's a possibility it goes to
zero. It's just a low probability
relative this. So everything that you
said for people that have not yet used
AI to the degree that you just
described.
If you want to get used to agents and
know the value they bring, you have to
have a conversation with it. And you
have to ask the question, but why? I'm
going to give all the parents out there
one thing. Every single parent that I
know has at le if if they have three
children, one of them has a pretty
severe anxiety problem almost assuredly
just based on the math.
The reason that anxiety is there is
because of technology and because we
don't converse as much as we used to and
get our feelings out. It is a very
powerful thing to be able to speak to
your parents with empathy and not be
judged and to go through this. And when
you consume things in X and you consume
things in Tik Tok and Instagram, your
brain's not getting relaxation. It's
getting constant opinions and judgments
and things like that. If you talk to AI,
hey, this is how I feel. I want to go
through it. Don't treat it as your
therapist. Just treat it as having a
conversation. I think the more people
have conversation with AI and realize
this is a an unbiased group. And if you
don't like the answers, you go to the
other LLM or you just ask the question
again. you will get different uh
questions. It's more about human beings
having conversations and connecting
dots. And that's what you were bringing
up. I'm I'm a believer that both the
school system, Google search, and this
whole searching for answers thing is a
major problem. Everything is an opinion.
You need to find ways to gather more
intelligence and gather more opinions on
your own life because only you know
about you. You know what's interesting
is um speaking of young kids. I think
I've talked previously about uh testing
the kids with AI. So you just ask, you
know, whatever your favorite model is,
you know, uh ask 10 questions for a
smart, you know, 5-year-old,
six-year-old, whatever. Um the kids love
it because they're talking to a machine
and you know, the questions are are uh
variable, etc. But one of the
interesting things is when a kid has a
question, you can actually tell the AI
to explain the pro and the con of this
to a six-year-old, 7-year-old, whatever.
And what it starts to do, what I've
noticed, is it starts to get them to
think not just as there's a single
answer, but that there's actually
multiple sides to what people think
about this. And so it's less almost
about the information as much as it is
like you're implicitly teaching the kid
how to think. And my kids are still
young, so like we'll see if that ends
up, you know, screwing them up or
helping them in their lifetime. But it
feels like something I didn't get
exposed to. Like there was no teacher
who was like, you know, here's the pros
and cons of the teacher was just like,
you know, the answer is C on the
multiple uh choice test and you know,
make sure you memorize that so that next
Friday you get it right on the on the
quiz. That's a very different way of
learning than you know kind of this
probabilistic thinking this this you
know two threedimensional um you know
kind of analysis of different topics.
>> Well that's when I did a paper on an AI
mindset I use three examples of what
you're saying. Um I call my own way that
I think about things as mosaic thinking.
I don't believe there's anything in life
where you make a decision and there
aren't multiple trade-offs that come
with that decision. And so I try to
think about all the trade-offs that come
with it and make a decision that I feel
most comfortable there. But if you're
not thinking about the trade-offs, I
don't want to go skiing because I might
die. Well, that's a that's only taking
one outcome into play. If I said that
skiing is the most relaxing thing I've
ever taught myself in my lifetime post
the age of 40, and it's one of the
greatest things that I believe I gave to
my kids as a gift. It's because skiing
down a mountain is a microcosm of life
and the trade-offs that came with me. I
could hurt my knee. I could hurt my
ankle. I could go through it. I thought
about all the benefits that would come
from my family. To watch my children at
3 and 5 years old be capable of doing
something that I can do, but they can do
it better by the time they're five to
give them confidence. I thought about so
many different things. Systems thinking.
So, you approach things from okay,
there's a bunch of things. How do we
start at this point, but at the end,
what are the benefits that will come?
Let me there's not just one benefit or
pro or con. There's many of them. The
Santa Fe Institute thinking holistically
on this whole thing and trying to get
being an FBI agent trained at Quantico,
they train your brain to go this way.
This is the benefits that come with AI
with doing exactly what you're saying.
And that's why a lot of the prompts I
have are look at what happened in this
context. So when I started this whole
thing up, I said in the contextual side,
inflation is much lower than I would
have expected in this context. That is
saying it's not that inflation is above
the 2% target. It's that oh my god, in
the context of what's happening, I would
think it would be much higher. We
printed so much money back in when we
have the unemployment rate near all-time
lows. The labor force participation rate
is going down. We've got ICE going into
cities. we're focused on reducing. All
of these things would suggest to me that
inflation would be higher. That's why
when you do it in the reverse and you
think of things in a contextual manner,
if I'm Kevin Worsh and I'm saying the
things I'm saying in front of Congress,
which is I'm going to have a forward
look at things as opposed to the answer
right now, which is it's above this. I
think you start making different
decisions. And I think what you just
brought up is really important for kids
to be learning right now because I think
the faster the world moves, the more the
information you get today is irrelevant
because the new news is already coming
out before you even process the old
news.
>> So, um, you mentioned, uh, ICE and I saw
this article, uh, a couple of weeks ago.
I just pulled it up. These numbers, I
think, are not quite, at least my
opinion as to what the effect on the
economy is. I think that there there's
some debate. So, let's talk about it.
ABC News says that US immigration
authorities removed more than 350,000
individuals so far in fiscal year 2026
according to the official ICE numbers.
Now, of that 350,000, they're saying
about 65,000 are still in detention
facilities in the US. 60% of those have
a criminal record according to the
agency, etc. There's still about 2
months or so left in the current fiscal
year, which ends September 30. So, B if
you kind of extrapolate that out, it'll
probably be over 400,000 um when uh when
it's done. Now, when you look at that,
that is an average of 1,400 arrests per
day in the month of June was the average
about 1450 or so.
There was a belief, I think, when a lot
of this started that deportations would
be deflationary. You're taking people
out of an economy and that should take
away demand for housing, for goods, for
all this stuff. Now, 350,000 400,000,
there's, you know, whatever 330 million
Americans, right, that live in the
country. So it's still a relatively
small number, but in certain areas I
have seen people try to correlate, hey,
there I has really been aggressive or
really been active in certain areas and
therefore is there an impact on price.
Forget for a second what the data says
theoretically. Do you buy into the
deportations are deflationary or do you
think that it is uh maybe inflationary
or or just has a minimal impact given
the numbers we're talking? Well, again,
I I think in the context of where we are
with everything else going on, meaning
the acceleration of AI, the fact that
we've got digital employees stepping
into the world right now in the fact
that we had a lot of people come into
the country where in in the prior years,
I think all of this stuff in the numbers
gets washed out by so many different
things that are moving at the exact same
time.
um if we hadn't had a rapid rise in
inflation to where inflation is a major
voting issue in this country. Now, the
year-over-year numbers,
honestly, what's the difference between
2 and a half and 2% in terms of like I
for people that are barely above the
poverty line, every basis point matters.
But when you're in a country with this
much well, from a GDP perspective, it
doesn't change anything. The reason it
has such an impact on inflation is,
trust me, I mean, I just got my latest
statement for car insurance on my Tesla.
It's insane. I mean, I literally said to
the person, you're telling me I have to
pay this much for a fivey year. I have a
5-year-old Tesla and in the value of the
Tesla versus this each year I'm paying
like 5 to 10% of the cost of the value
of it today. Now, why is that there?
Because we printed tons of money from
2020 to save us from a pandemic. So, the
reason I brought all that up is not to
avoid the question. It's that that can
be thrown into the mix with all of these
other things that are going on and
there's no way to know the answer and
it's an issue that is a hot button issue
for people in the country. I saw a
protest just yesterday in a street
corner in Maine, a random street corner
with seven people protesting ICE. So,
this is a a situation that I think when
you're reading stats, the ones you're
reading, those are published by someone
for some reason. There's another stat
which is published for someone for
another reason. And so I don't know what
you're, you know, what anyone's reading
that is true. I don't know how you know
the numbers that are true. I'm just
going to say when you bring up inflation
or deflation, there's a lot of factors
going on. And I try not to get caught in
where they are today. I get caught more
on where do I think everything will be
in 3 years from now. And I think
inflation is going to have a lot of
headwinds to go higher.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Galaxy 1. A lot of people have their
money working for them, but now the
question is how hard is it working? And
Galaxy 1, they got a different approach.
Everyone earns 3.5% APY with Galaxy 1
Cash. And if you make over 200 grand a
year, that means you're rich. You make
over 200 grand a year, you probably
qualify as an accredited investor, which
unlocks 8% yield guaranteed by Galaxy
Digital. Now, the best part though is
that you can set that interest to
automatically reinvest straight into
your favorite stocks, ETFs, or crypto.
You don't have to think about it every
month. Right now, this second, Galaxy
1's running a crazy promo. You can get a
$3,000 cash bonus when you deposit
$10,000 or more in cash or crypto. If
your cash isn't working as hard as you,
it's time to make a move. Sign up and
start earning today at galaxy.app/p
app/p to be eligible for the $3,000
bonus. Again, galaxy.appp.
Go check them out today. These uh micro
protests, there's there's I've seen a
number of them in New York City and it's
usually, you know, I don't know, less
than 30 people. Um, and they've got
signs and they're actually like uh well
produced if if that's a way to describe
it. Like, you know, like they have
signs, they're they're organized,
whatever. But it's a small number of
people. And it's not always clear what
they're protesting, but they generally
have a direction, right? They don't like
the current administration. They don't
like the deportations, whatever it is.
And one of the aspects that I actually
think is maybe most interesting is
usually in the ones I've seen, they're
not a lot of young people. It's usually
middle-ag and older people. And so, you
know, I don't know what to read into
that. Some of it may just be like, hey,
people, you know, young people don't
want to go stand out on the street
corner. They'd rather like post on
social media about this stuff. some of
it maybe they're like working at their
job and you know they don't have time to
do this. Um but it might not be that
different than what's happened in the
past. Like there's always been protest
against governments and you know all
this kind of stuff. So I find it very
fascinating that there's so much media
coverage of it all. But again, I think
maybe what your point is is like if you
can insulate yourself from like what
everyone yell and screaming about and
just look at like companies are growing
faster than the S&P is growing in terms
of their earnings and their data, that
is way more important than like what's
happening on your local street corner in
terms of is there a protest or not. Like
there's noise and then there is the
signal. And I think what you're really
maybe one lesson for me taking out of
this conversation is just like if
earnings are growing faster then the
company's value is going up that likely
means that there's a lot more runway to
go in those companies than not.
>> So we very seldom talk about anything
political. I don't I don't know if we
really have. Um and I think that's a
function at least from my side. I can't
speak for you. I I I don't think about
those in the context of investing. I
actually believe that one of the reasons
that the University of Michigan consumer
confidence level is at all-time lows is
because if you break it down by the
politics, Republicans right now are much
more positive than Democrats. If we had
a Democratic president, the numbers
would be flipped.
>> And so that doesn't really help me
invest. The only part that I care about
is if you're a person watching this and
you believe that the country is going to
blow up because of what's going on with
ICE or you believe because of ICE I want
to invest more money. Both of you are
wrong.
The market is moving on earnings, the
market is moving on what's happening
with AI and political issues, religious
debates, war debates. It's driven by
what's happening from the economy and
what's happening with earnings. and it
always falls back into place. If the
earnings don't fall a year from now and
you're growing at some pace based on
history, the market is very likely to be
higher. What is happening is we're
seeing multiple compression. You would
have expected with this kind of year
that the S&P would be up more because
the earnings are up 30 are going to be
up 30 plus% and the S&P is unless it
really accelerates is not going to be up
that much. That is kind of where I
answer the question for me without
politics. What do I think is disrupting
the stock market? And I believe it is
the negative side of AI. Bernie Sanders
came out this week and made a very big
political statement on AI almost like a
threat about the people involved in it.
Anthropic and open AI even though it
wasn't a threat, but it's a political
issue and they want to stop data centers
and they want to stop this and go
through this. I don't get involved in
that. I deal with the facts of are the
data centers still being plugged in?
Yes. Are we going to grow? Yes. If I was
living near a data center, would I move
away from it for my kids? Yeah, I
probably would. That's my choice in this
situation. That's as political as I am.
You tell me the rules. I will adjust to
what I think the rules are going to be.
And if I don't like the rules in here,
I'll either fight to get them changed or
I'll go move somewhere else and just
figure a way to go through it. I just
try not to get through this unless it's
impacting my kids and the way that I
live my life. I just think human beings
and governments and friction, this stuff
happens and it's going to continue to
happen. I just hope that people can be
happy every day and that's the only
thing that I'm trying to impact.
>> You know what's interesting to me about
the data centers? Uh Texas just came out
with not not a moratorum but kind of
like a let's slow down and think about
this and and talk through and and you
know kind of collaborate maybe is the
the right way to think about it. I saw
multiple AI companies, I believe Caruso,
HUD 8, there's probably some others, um,
that build data centers be like, we
agree with this, we want to work with
the government, etc. That's a very
different response than the software AI
companies, which have been very abrasive
towards the government. And so it does
feel like uh when you're building
physical things in the real world,
reality kind of tethers everyone to the
ground like either you can build or you
can't, right? there's no like, you know,
our engineers are just fine working in
our office and then we'll figure out if
we can sell it later. And so, uh, I
thought it was actually a pretty
positive development that you have in a
state that tends to be, you know, or at
least thought of as more kind of
conservativeleaning and and, you know,
pro- uh, business, less regulation, etc.
You actually have the AI data center
builders and the government all
coalescing around this idea of like,
let's work together, let's figure this
out. But we understand there's trade-off
decisions to be made and we need both
sides to come together and and figure
this out. That's very different than say
in New York where they're just like,
"Hey, it's a blanket ban. We're not
going to do this." And you know, the AI
people are all freaking out because they
feel like they're, you know, under
attack.
So my my because of where we are in
technology right now and because time is
moving much faster, this fits in my time
category and this is the way I've kind
of processed it. if the so I don't have
a problem at all with parents not
wanting a terapab near their kids or a
data center near their kids we don't
have enough data and you only find out
afterwards if the radiation if this if
that impacts and there isn't enough time
to go through it's the same way I felt
about the vaccines the people that have
problem with taking the vaccine after co
when it didn't go through the normal
vetting process on a new technology
that's their own personal opinion and
they should have that and go through it
For the people that did it that are
really worried and it brought them
comfort, they should go through it. The
benefit that comes from the data center
push back and the friction for the
people who like I agree that voters
should have a right. Elon Musk is
thinking now about space. So I don't
know if you've heard this, but there are
people that don't believe we should
build them in space either because the
debris could fall. We're getting too
busy. Like there's humans are never
going to be happy, Anthony. There will
never be a time that everyone's going to
be like, you know what, that's a good
idea. I think we're all on the same page
with that. So,
>> let's go underground. He's going to bore
the tunnels. Let's go underground. Then
>> that's the what separates us from from
animals. And animals, they just they
fight it out. They kill each other. Do
whatever. We're trying to live in packs
of people. as sapiens went through, we
are the only species on the planet that
can live I forget what the numbers are
uh in in greater than what is it like 50
50 uh without killing each other. Um
we're just always going to disagree
because we've got this thing between our
heads and I think it's a good thing
because if one person says we can't do
this then a human will go well let's
figure out a way that we can satisfy
that problem and still get it done. Then
there'll be another complaint. then we
come up with another one. That is what
creative destruction is. Is you actually
need the friction, the not agreeing to
come up with a better idea. And because
we have AI now, we will keep coming up
with more and more ideas. No way
everyone will ever be satisfied with any
decision. And that's just the way it's
going to be with humans forever, ever,
ever.
>> I don't think it's a bad thing either.
>> I don't I don't either.
>> It ends up in a uh in a better spot. Um,
all right. Anybody who is uh who's
watching this, if you do not watch
Jord's video on Sundays, what are you
doing? You're you're lost in the sauce.
Let's go. Go to YouTube, search Jordy
Visser. He does a video every single
Sunday, which is like this is uh this is
for the smooth brains. This is for the
like, you know, me people and the
smaller brains here. Little watered down
version. Call it Jordy Light. On Sunday,
you get the full package. You know, you
get the whole analysis, deep, in-depth.
Uh uses big SAT words and uh you know,
really makes everyone educated.
>> I hated school. I don't have big SAT
words unless they come from AI.
>> I just want to call out earlier you
said, you know, I think a lot. That was
like the best line ever.
>> I I think a lot. I don't worry a lot.
That's the difference. I don't worry a
lot. I think a lot. So,
>> yeah.
>> One ask I do have.
>> All right. What's your What's your ask?
>> It's not for you. It's for the audience.
Um, so
I've been working all summer, not the
entire summer, but in the points that I
don't not working on other things on
making sure that, and this is for the
crypto community, my job I feel
beginning in September in for the
following year is what we talked about
with figure today. I need data to do a
30 to 60 minute video twice a month to
start and then every week going forward
in the same format that I do my regular
weekly one. These are educational
things. I need to to basically explain
to hedge fund people, mutual fund
people, all of the people that have
turned Anthony away when he's tried to
raise money from them in the past uh to
be involved with crypto to get people to
buy Bitcoin. I need the best websites,
the best data, the best everything. For
me to be successful at this, I need to
create a data-driven story every week of
what's happening in the most important
tokens around crypto and show people the
stories that are happening. I've been
collecting this data. There's been
really good people out there that are
helping me, but I figure this audience
is loaded with a lot of smart people.
Jordy wants to do a regular video where
he helps the community, but he needs
more information, more data. He needs to
speak to people. the complaint I gave
about figure about not speaking to
management. I'm getting more involved.
The Bitcoin Policy Institute reached
out. I had a great conversation with
them. I'm trying to speak to smarter
people in the space that are ready for
the launchpad because the launchpad is
here, guys. And I want to be involved
with spreading the word.
You hear that noise? That's me calling
Mike Kagny. Mike, let's go. Don't worry.
I got you. All right. Send Jordy all
your ideas. Make sure that you get him
websites, data, things that he should be
reading. If you uh create content, this
your shot. Shoot your shot at Jordy. If
you don't create content, but you like
someone who does, then go ahead and tell
him so he can get some uh some
information.
>> I just put my my email address, and I
hate to do this.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Jordy-labs.com.
That is jordisser
with a hyphenlabs.com.
>> Give me your cell phone number. I dare
you. Nope, not doing that. I'll be too
big. My phone rang three times while we
did this.
All right, we'll see you guys next week.